<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><xml><records><record><database name="uleam_endnote.enl" path="uleam_endnote.enl">uleam_endnote.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Ortega-Andrade, Mauricio</author><author>Prieto-Torres, David A.</author><author>Gómez-Lora, Ignacio</author><author>Lizcano, Diego J.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Ecological and Geographical Analysis of the Distribution of the Mountain Tapir (Tapirus pinchaque) in Ecuador: Importance of Protected Areas in Future Scenarios of Global Warming</title><secondary-title>PLoS ONE</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>PLoS ONE</full-title></periodical><pages>In press</pages><keywords/><dates><year>2015</year></dates><urls/><abstract>In Ecuador, Tapirus pinchaque is considered to be critically endangered. Although the species has been registered in several localities, its geographic distribution remains unclear, and the effects of climate change and current land uses on this species are largely unknown. We modeled the ecological niche of T. pinchaque using MaxEnt, in order to assess its potential adaptation to present and future climate change scenarios. We evaluated the effects of habitat loss due by current land use, the ecosystem availability and importance of Ecuadorian System of Protected Areas into the models. The model of environmental suitability estimated an extent of occurrence for species of 21,729 km2 in all of Ecuador, mainly occurring along the corridor of the eastern Ecuadorian Andes. A total of 10 Andean ecosystems encompassed ~98% of the area defined by the model, with herbaceous paramo, northeastern Andean montane evergreen forest and southeastern Andean montane evergreen forest being the most representative. When considering the effect of habitat loss, a significant reduction in model area (~17%) occurred, and the effect of climate change represented a net reduction of 3.03 to 37.86%. However, the synergistic effect of both climate change and habitat loss, given current land use practices, could represent a greater risk in the short-term, leading to a net reduction of 19.90 to 44.65% in T. pinchaque’s potential distribution. Even under such a scenarios, several Protected Areas harbor a portion (~42-47%) of the potential distribution defined by the models. However, the central and southern sections of the country are highly threatened by habitat loss and climate change. Based on these results and due to the restricted home range of T. pinchaque, its preference for upland forests and paramos and its small estimated population size in the Andes, we suggest to maintaining its current status as Critically Endangered in Ecuador.</abstract></record><record><database name="uleam_endnote.enl" path="uleam_endnote.enl">uleam_endnote.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Santacruz, S</author><author>Rivadeneira, C</author><author>Castro, M</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Edible films based on starch and chitosan. Effect of starch source and concentration, plasticizer, surfactant's hydrophobic tail and mechanical treatment</title><secondary-title>Food Hydrocolloids</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Food Hydrocolloids</full-title></periodical><pages>89-94</pages><volume>49</volume><keywords/><dates><year>2015</year></dates><publisher>Elsevier {BV}</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.1016/j.foodhyd.2015.03.019</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.foodhyd.2015.03.019</url><url>http://linkinghub.elsevier.com/retrieve/pii/S0268005X15001320</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>Edible films based on starch and chitosan were obtained by varying the starch source (potato and cassava starch), starch concentration (0.5 and 1.0%), type of plasticizer (glucose and glycerol), chain length of the surfactant's hydrophobic tail (12 or 18 carbons) and mechanical treatment (0.5 or 4 min stirring time) during the preparation of the film forming solution. A completely randomized design with factorial arrangement 2(4) was utilized. The variables to be determined were film opacity, film thickness, tensile strength, water vapor permeability, elasticity and film solubility. Starch source, starch concentration and type of plasticizer were the most important factors to be consider on formulation of edible films based on starch. Those factors affect to most of the evaluated film properties, except opacity and elasticity. Stirring time may be a valuable and economic tool to improve elasticity, whereas the use of an appropriate surfactant may help to improve the tensile strength of the starch film. (C) 2015 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</abstract></record><record><database name="uleam_endnote.enl" path="uleam_endnote.enl">uleam_endnote.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Slik, J W Ferry</author><author>Arroyo-Rodríguez, Víctor</author><author>Aiba, Shin-Ichiro</author><author>Alvarez-Loayza, Patricia</author><author>Alves, Luciana F</author><author>Ashton, Peter</author><author>Balvanera, Patricia</author><author>Bastian, Meredith L</author><author>Bellingham, Peter J</author><author>van den Berg, Eduardo</author><author>Bernacci, Luis</author><author>da Conceição Bispo, Polyanna</author><author>Blanc, Lilian</author><author>Böhning-Gaese, Katrin</author><author>Boeckx, Pascal</author><author>Bongers, Frans</author><author>Boyle, Brad</author><author>Bradford, Matt</author><author>Brearley, Francis Q</author><author>Breuer-Ndoundou Hockemba, Mireille</author><author>Bunyavejchewin, Sarayudh</author><author>Calderado Leal Matos, Darley</author><author>Castillo-Santiago, Miguel</author><author>Catharino, Eduardo L M</author><author>Chai, Shauna-Lee</author><author>Chen, Yukai</author><author>Colwell, Robert K</author><author>Robin, Chazdon L.</author><author>Clark, Connie</author><author>Clark, David B.</author><author>Clark, Deborah A</author><author>Culmsee, Heike</author><author>Damas, Kipiro</author><author>Dattaraja, Handanakere S</author><author>Dauby, Gilles</author><author>Davidar, Priya</author><author>DeWalt, Saara J</author><author>Doucet, Jean-Louis</author><author>Duque, Alvaro</author><author>Durigan, Giselda</author><author>Eichhorn, Karl A O</author><author>Eisenlohr, Pedro V</author><author>Eler, Eduardo</author><author>Ewango, Corneille</author><author>Farwig, Nina</author><author>Feeley, Kenneth J</author><author>Ferreira, Leandro</author><author>Field, Richard</author><author>de Oliveira Filho, Ary T</author><author>Fletcher, Christine</author><author>Forshed, Olle</author><author>Franco, Geraldo</author><author>Fredriksson, Gabriella</author><author>Gillespie, Thomas</author><author>Gillet, Jean-François</author><author>Amarnath, Giriraj</author><author>Griffith, Daniel M</author><author>Grogan, James</author><author>Gunatilleke, Nimal</author><author>Harris, David</author><author>Harrison, Rhett</author><author>Hector, Andy</author><author>Homeier, Jürgen</author><author>Imai, Nobuo</author><author>Itoh, Akira</author><author>Jansen, Patrick A</author><author>Joly, Carlos A</author><author>de Jong, Bernardus H J</author><author>Kartawinata, Kuswata</author><author>Kearsley, Elizabeth</author><author>Kelly, Daniel L</author><author>Kenfack, David</author><author>Kessler, Michael</author><author>Kitayama, Kanehiro</author><author>Kooyman, Robert</author><author>Larney, Eileen</author><author>Laumonier, Yves</author><author>Laurance, Susan</author><author>Laurance, William F</author><author>Lawes, Michael J</author><author>Amaral, Ieda Leao do</author><author>Letcher, Susan G</author><author>Lindsell, Jeremy</author><author>Lu, Xinghui</author><author>Mansor, Asyraf</author><author>Marjokorpi, Antti</author><author>Martin, Emanuel H</author><author>Meilby, Henrik</author><author>Melo, Felipe P L</author><author>Metcalfe, Daniel J</author><author>Medjibe, Vincent P</author><author>Metzger, Jean Paul</author><author>Millet, Jerome</author><author>Mohandass, D</author><author>Montero, Juan C</author><author>de Morisson Valeriano, Márcio</author><author>Mugerwa, Badru</author><author>Nagamasu, Hidetoshi</author><author>Nilus, Reuben</author><author>Ochoa-Gaona, Susana</author><author>Onrizal</author><author>Page, Navendu</author><author>Parolin, Pia</author><author>Parren, Marc</author><author>Parthasarathy, Narayanaswamy</author><author>Paudel, Ekananda</author><author>Permana, Andrea</author><author>Piedade, Maria T F</author><author>Pitman, Nigel C A</author><author>Poorter, Lourens</author><author>Poulsen, Axel D.</author><author>Poulsen, John</author><author>Powers, Jennifer</author><author>Prasad, Rama C</author><author>Puyravaud, Jean-Philippe</author><author>Razafimahaimodison, Jean-Claude</author><author>Reitsma, Jan</author><author>dos Santos, João Roberto</author><author>Roberto Spironello, Wilson</author><author>Romero-Saltos, Hugo</author><author>Rovero, Francesco</author><author>Rozak, Andes Hamuraby</author><author>Ruokolainen, Kalle</author><author>Rutishauser, Ervan</author><author>Saiter, Felipe</author><author>Saner, Philippe</author><author>Santos, Braulio A.</author><author>Santos, Fernanda</author><author>Sarker, Swapan K</author><author>Satdichanh, Manichanh</author><author>Schmitt, Christine B</author><author>Schöngart, Jochen</author><author>Schulze, Mark</author><author>Suganuma, Marcio S</author><author>Sheil, Douglas</author><author>da Silva Pinheiro, Eduardo</author><author>Sist, Plinio</author><author>Stevart, Tariq</author><author>Sukumar, Raman</author><author>Sun, I.-Fang</author><author>Sunderand, Terry</author><author>Suresh, H S</author><author>Suzuki, Eizi</author><author>Tabarelli, Marcelo</author><author>Tang, Jangwei</author><author>Targhetta, Natália</author><author>Theilade, Ida</author><author>Thomas, Duncan W</author><author>Tchouto, Peguy</author><author>Hurtado, Johanna</author><author>Valencia, Renato</author><author>van Valkenburg, Johan L C H</author><author>Van Do, Tran</author><author>Vasquez, Rodolfo</author><author>Verbeeck, Hans</author><author>Adekunle, Victor</author><author>Vieira, Simone A</author><author>Webb, Campbell O</author><author>Whitfeld, Timothy</author><author>Wich, Serge A</author><author>Williams, John</author><author>Wittmann, Florian</author><author>Wöll, Hannsjoerg</author><author>Yang, Xiaobo</author><author>Adou Yao, C. Yves</author><author>Yap, Sandra L</author><author>Yoneda, Tsuyoshi</author><author>Zahawi, Rakan A</author><author>Zakaria, Rahmad</author><author>Zang, Runguo</author><author>de Assis, Rafael L</author><author>Garcia Luize, Bruno</author><author>Venticinque, Eduardo M</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>An estimate of the number of tropical tree species</title><secondary-title>Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</full-title></periodical><pages>201423147</pages><volume>112</volume><issue>24</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2015</year></dates><publisher>Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.1073/pnas.1423147112</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1423147112</url><url>http://www.pnas.org/lookup/doi/10.1073/pnas.1423147112</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>The high species richness of tropical forests has long been recognized, yet there remains substantial uncertainty regarding the actual number of tropical tree species. Using a pantropical tree inventory database from closed canopy forests, consisting of 657,630 trees belonging to 11,371 species, we use a fitted value of Fisher's alpha and an approximate pantropical stem total to estimate the minimum number of tropical forest tree species to fall between similar to 40,000 and similar to 53,000, i.e., at the high end of previous estimates. Contrary to common assumption, the Indo-Pacific region was found to be as species-rich as the Neotropics, with both regions having a minimum of similar to 19,000-25,000 tree species. Continental Africa is relatively depauperate with a minimum of similar to 4,500-6,000 tree species. Very few species are shared among the African, American, and the Indo-Pacific regions. We provide a methodological framework for estimating species richness in trees that may help refine species richness estimates of tree-dependent taxa.</abstract></record><record><database name="uleam_endnote.enl" path="uleam_endnote.enl">uleam_endnote.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Macías-Mayorga, Dayanara</author><author>Laiz, Irene</author><author>Moreno-Garrido, Ignacio</author><author>Blasco, Julián</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Is oxidative stress related to cadmium accumulation in the Mollusc Crassostrea angulata?</title><secondary-title>Aquatic Toxicology</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Aquatic Toxicology</full-title></periodical><pages>231-241</pages><volume>161</volume><keywords/><dates><year>2015</year></dates><publisher>Elsevier {BV}</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.1016/j.aquatox.2015.02.007</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.aquatox.2015.02.007</url><url>http://linkinghub.elsevier.com/retrieve/pii/S0166445X15000582</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>The kinetics of cadmium (Cd) accumulation in the gills and digestive gland of Crassotrea angulata at three concentrations of cadmium (0.088 mu M, 0.44 mu M and 2.22 mu M) was monitored for 28 days. The relationship between accumulation and toxicity was studied using metallothionein-like protein (MTLP) concentration and reduced glutathione levels (GSH) as biochemical endpoints. The activity of enzymes which form part of the antioxidant defense system, in particular glutathione reductase (GR), total glutathione peroxidase (GPx), superoxide dismutase (SOD) and catalase (CAT), as enzymatic endpoints, was also assessed. A first order kinetic model demonstrated that the accumulation process does not take place linearly, as the Cd concentration in gills and digestive gland tended toward a stationary state. Metallothionein-like protein is clearly induced by Cd accumulation; however, at high Cd concentrations the detoxification mechanism of this protein is affected. High Cd concentrations (2.22 mu M) lead to a decrease in GSH levels, and also inhibit antioxidant enzyme activities, demonstrating the adverse effect of this metal on the antioxidant balance system. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</abstract></record><record><database name="uleam_endnote.enl" path="uleam_endnote.enl">uleam_endnote.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>MORALES-SERNA, FRANCISCO NEPTALI</author><author>CAÑA-BOZADA, VÍCTOR</author><author>MERA-LOOR, GEORMERY</author><author>LOOR-ANDRADE, PEGGY</author><author>FAJER-ÁVILA, EMMA J</author><author>HO, JU-SHEY</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>New records of sea lice (Copepoda: Caligidae) from marine fishes in Jaramijó, an area with potential for sea-cage aquaculture in Ecuador</title><secondary-title>Zootaxa</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Zootaxa</full-title></periodical><pages>366</pages><volume>3920</volume><issue>2</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2015</year></dates><publisher>Magnolia Press</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.11646/zootaxa.3920.2.8</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.11646/zootaxa.3920.2.8</url><url>http://biotaxa.org/Zootaxa/article/view/zootaxa.3920.2.8</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>Farming of finfish in sea cages is gaining popularity worldwide. These systems are a suitable environment for the emergence, establishment and transmission of parasites or pathogens, such as sea lice (Copepoda: Caligidae), known to cause serious diseases and economic losses in finfish aquaculture worldwide. In coastal waters of Jaramijó, Ecuador, there are plans to culture spotted rose snapper (Lutjanus guttatus) and longfin yellowtail (Seriola rivoliana); however, the information about the occurrence of sea lice on fish from this country is scarce. To address this problem, a parasitological survey of economically important fish caught by artisanal fishermen was conducted between June 2013 and May 2014. A total of 608 fish belonging to 66 species were examined. Sea lice were found on 23 fish species. The diversity of these parasites consisted of 22 species of Caligus and 5 species of Lepeophtheirus. Most sea lice species (66%) occurred in a single fish species only, with low infection levels. The most frequently encountered species were Caligus asperimanus Pearse, 1951, Caligus mutabilis Wilson, 1905 and Caligus rufimaculatus Wilson, 1905. Taxonomic remarks are presented for some of the species recorded during this survey. All but two sea lice records are new to Ecuador, considerably expanding the geographical range of some species.</abstract></record><record><database name="uleam_endnote.enl" path="uleam_endnote.enl">uleam_endnote.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Cabanillas-Terán, Nancy</author><author>Martín, José A</author><author>Rodríguez-Barreras, Ruber</author><author>Luque, Ángel</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Size-density strategy displayed by Diadema africanum linked with the stability of urchin-barrens in the Canary Islands</title><secondary-title>Journal of the Marine Biological Association of the United Kingdom</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Journal of the Marine Biological Association of the United Kingdom</full-title></periodical><pages>145-151</pages><volume>95</volume><issue>01</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2015</year></dates><publisher>Cambridge University Press ({CUP})</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.1017/S0025315414001246</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S0025315414001246</url><url>http://www.journals.cambridge.org/abstract_S0025315414001246</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>The sea urchin Diadema africanum is considered a key herbivore in sublittoral ecosystems of the Canary Islands. Spatial and temporal variability in population structure was carried out at Gran Canaria. We performed a morphometric and population density analysis during 2005, 2006 and 2007 at four sites in zones of Gran Canaria. The study considered a vertical gradient (5, 10 and 20 m depth) during both seasons, the cold season (February and March) and the warm season (October and November). The sea urchin D. africanum in Gran Canaria exhibited an overall density of 7.59 +/- 2.92 urchin m(-2). A two-way ANOVA evidenced spatial differences in mean abundance of the species, while seasonality was not relevant. The vertical analysis of the abundance of D. africanum showed differences, the smaller sizes appeared at greater depths. The Aristotle's lantern width decreased in a vertical gradient, being remarkable between 10 and 20 m. Findings of uniformity in size over time, a stable range of high densities and the lack of a relationship between the size of the sea urchins and the season reveals that the density-size strategy displayed by D. africanum which explains in turns the high stability of the urchin barrens, which, once developed, remain as areas of permanent desertification in subtidal depths throughout the Canary Archipelago.</abstract></record><record><database name="uleam_endnote.enl" path="uleam_endnote.enl">uleam_endnote.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Romero-Caicedo, A F</author><author>Galván-Magaña, F</author><author>Martínez-Ortiz, J</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Reproduction of the pelagic thresher shark Alopias pelagicus in the equatorial Pacific</title><secondary-title>Journal of the Marine Biological Association of the United Kingdom</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Journal of the Marine Biological Association of the United Kingdom</full-title></periodical><pages>1-7</pages><volume>FirstView</volume><issue>07</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2014</year></dates><publisher>Cambridge University Press ({CUP})</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.1017/S0025315414000927</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S0025315414000927</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>ABSTRACT The reproductive biology of the pelagic thresher shark Alopias pelagicus, was analysed based on 241 individuals (101 males and 140 females). Samples were collected from April 2005 to February 2006, from the artisanal fishery in Manta, Ecuador. Males ranged from 68 to 183 cm precaudal length (PL); females ranged from 70 to 180 cm PL. In embryos, sexual proportion was 1F:1M; while in adults the proportion was 1.4F:1M, which suggests sexual segregation in maturing individuals. We showed differences in the development of reproductive structures according to the reproductive condition, and in males the size at maturity occurs at 144.3 cm PL and in females at 151.4 cm PL. We recorded 33 pregnant females that presented one embryo in each uterus in different developmental stages. The results of this study provide information on reproduction of the species that will help to establish an appropriate fisheries management.</abstract></record><record><database name="uleam_endnote.enl" path="uleam_endnote.enl">uleam_endnote.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Gómez, Samuel</author><author>Morales-Serna, F Neptalí</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Updated checklist of published and unpublished records of harpacticoid copepods (Crustacea: Copepoda: Harpacticoida) from Mexico</title><secondary-title>Proceedings of the Biological Society of Washington</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Proceedings of the Biological Society of Washington</full-title></periodical><pages>99-121</pages><volume>127</volume><issue>1</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2014</year></dates><publisher>The Biological Society of Washington</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.2988/0006-324x-127.1.99</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.2988/0006-324X-127.1.99</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>An account of previous lists and descriptions of marine and freshwater harpacticoid copepods of Mexico yielded, by year 2010, 71 marine and 21 freshwater species from a variety of habitats. Sediment samples from the littoral zone to more than 2000 m depth along the Mexican Pacific coast, from the west coast of the Baja California peninsula, from the Gulf of Mexico, and from anchialine caves and cenotes from Yucatan, were taken during the last 15 yr as a continued effort to improve our knowledge of the diversity of the harpacticoid fauna from Mexico. This study shows that, at present, 151 species/subspecies distributed in 85 genera and 31 families are known from Mexican marine and freshwater systems. Additionally, a number of species belonging to 78 genera and 25 families are yet to be described. The checklist contains information on the locality, geographic coordinates, habitat, and source of the recorded taxa. There is a better knowledge of the harpacticoids from Sinaloa (northwestern Mexico). However, the number of species from Mexico is expected to grow rapidly in the forthcoming years.</abstract></record><record><database name="uleam_endnote.enl" path="uleam_endnote.enl">uleam_endnote.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Figueroa, Juan</author><author>Mero, David</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Length of capture and reproduction of green spiny lobster Panulirus gracilis (Decapoda: Palinuridae) from the coast of Manabi, Ecuador</title><secondary-title>Revista de Biología Tropical</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Revista de Biología Tropical</full-title></periodical><pages>1189-1199</pages><volume>61</volume><issue>3</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2013</year></dates><publisher>Universidad de Costa Rica</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.15517/rbt.v61i3.11924</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.15517/rbt.v61i3.11924</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>Green spiny lobster Panulirus gracilis is an economical resource of high importance for fishermen populations in the continental coast of Ecuador. Traditionally, this specie is captured using gillnets and semiautonomous diving system (hookah). With the objective to analyze some biological aspects about this fishery in Manabi, we examined lengths of capture (carapace length: CL and abdominal length: AL), sex ratio and reproductive aspects in females between June and September 2010. A total of 415 females and 288 males were captured with gillnets in El Mangle-Puerto Cayo (Central coast, depth: 3-6m), and by diving in Puerto Lopez-Salango (South coast, depth: 7-12m). Sex ratio from males to females was 0.72:1 for gillnets, and 0.63:1 for diving. Lobsters captured by diving were larger (84.1 +/- 3.3mm CL) than lobsters captured by gillnets (73.4 +/- 2.9mm CL). Percentage of ovigerous females captured by diving was higher than females captured by gillnets. There was a pattern between lengths by sex (relation AL vs. CL), females were larger than males at same CL. Differences found between lengths and the occurrence of ovigerous females could be related with depth where capture methods are used. A total of 98% of landed lobsters were smaller than legal captured length and we recommend the establishment of a monitoring evaluation program during the fishing season, and a ban, in order to evaluate the natural fluctuation in length and reproductive stages of green spiny lobster in the coasts of Manabi.</abstract></record><record><database name="uleam_endnote.enl" path="uleam_endnote.enl">uleam_endnote.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Loor-Andrade, P</author><author>Galván-Magaña, F</author><author>Elorriaga-Verplancken, F R</author><author>Polo-Silva, C</author><author>Delgado-Huertas, A</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Population and individual foraging patterns of two hammerhead sharks using carbon and nitrogen stable isotopes</title><secondary-title>Rapid Communications in Mass Spectrometry</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Rapid Communications in Mass Spectrometry</full-title></periodical><pages>821-829</pages><volume>29</volume><issue>9</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2015</year></dates><publisher>Wiley-Blackwell</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.1002/rcm.7169</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/rcm.7169</url><url>http://doi.wiley.com/10.1002/rcm.7169</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>RATIONALE: Individual foraging behavior is an important variable of predators commonly studied at the population level. Some hammerhead shark species play a significant role in the marine ecosystem as top consumers. In this context, stable isotope analysis allows us to infer some ecological metrics and patterns that cannot usually be obtained using traditional methods. METHODS: We determined the isotopic composition (delta C-13 and delta N-15 values) of dorsal muscle and vertebrae of Sphyrna lewini and Sphyrna zygaena using a continuous-flow system consisting of an elemental analyzer combined with a Delta Plus XL mass spectrometer. Foraging variability by sex and by individual was inferred from the isotopic values. RESULTS: There were no significant differences in the isotopic values of muscle samples between sexes, but there were differences between species. The trophic niche breadth of the two species was similar and overlap was low. A low niche overlap was observed between S. lewini individual vertebrae. We found differences in the delta N-15 values of S. zygaena vertebrae, with lower values in the first group of samples. CONCLUSIONS: Despite these hammerhead shark species inhabiting the same area, there was low trophic niche overlap between species and individuals, due to different individual foraging strategies, according to the carbon and nitrogen isotopic profiles obtained. The use of tissues that retain lifetime isotopic information is useful to complement studies on trophic ecology. Copyright (C) 2015 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</abstract></record><record><database name="uleam_endnote.enl" path="uleam_endnote.enl">uleam_endnote.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Valle, David Mero-del</author><author>Castillo-Ruperti, Ricardo</author><author>Figueroa-Pico, Juan</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Distribución de tallas y potencial reproductivo de hembras de langosta verde Panulirus gracilis (Decapoda: Palinuridae) en Santa Rosa Manabí Ecuador</title><secondary-title>Revista de biología marina y oceanografía</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Revista de biología marina y oceanografía</full-title></periodical><pages>125-134</pages><volume>50</volume><issue>1</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2015</year></dates><publisher>{SciELO} Comision Nacional de Investigacion Cientifica Y Tecnologica ({CONICYT})</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.4067/s0718-19572015000100010</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.4067/S0718-19572015000100010</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>Spiny lobster Panulirus gracilis is a fishing resource of high commercial importance in Ecuador. Studies of fecundity and reproductive potential of population are fundamental and ensures sustainable use for the fishery, because it is intimately related with the renewal capacity of population. We analyzed size distribution and reproductive potential of spiny lobsters P. gracilis catched by nets in Santa Rosa, Manabi, Ecuador. Data was collected during July 2011, August, September and November 2012, and a sample of 273 females was obtained. Size of lobsters varied between 58 and 102 mm of carapace length (CL), with an average of 83 mm CL +/- 7.1; only 2% of lobsters had legal size (&gt; 103 mm LC). Thirty percent of females were ovigerous stage III. Fecundity varied between 123,255 and 805,632 eggs, with an average of 397,115 +/- 148,069 eggs; relative fecundity was 1193 +/- 236 eggs for each gram of weight. Reproductive potential analysis showed that females with size &lt; 80 mm CL contribute only with 17.8% of total egg production while females between 90 and 100 mm CL provide 38.2% of total eggs production.</abstract></record><record><database name="uleam_endnote.enl" path="uleam_endnote.enl">uleam_endnote.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Araujo, Cristiano V. M.</author><author>Moreira-Santos, Matilde</author><author>Patricio, Joana</author><author>Martins, Irene</author><author>Moreno-Garrido, Ignacio</author><author>Blasco, Julan</author><author>Marques, Joao C.</author><author>Ribeiro, Rui</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Feeding niche preference of the mudsnail Peringia ulvae</title><secondary-title>Marine and Freshwater Research</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Marine and Freshwater Research</full-title></periodical><pages>573</pages><volume>66</volume><issue>7</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2015</year></dates><publisher>{CSIRO} Publishing</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.1071/MF14021</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1071/MF14021</url><url>http://www.publish.csiro.au/?paper=MF14021</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>The feeding behaviour of Peringia ulvae was studied with the aim of assessing its preferential feeding niche (habit) as well as its potential role in controlling or preventing the occurrence of macroalgal blooms. Both these aspects were studied in the Mondego estuary because of the clear long-lasting eutrophication process that favours the growth of two opportunistic macroalgae, Gracilaria spp. and Ulva spp., over the local beds of the macrophyte Zostera nolteii, which is another potential food source. All three species, both with and without periphyton, were used as a single food source in feeding experiments to assess different feeding parameters of the gastropod. Sediment with microphytobenthos was used together with the latter three species in feeding niche preference experiments. None of the food types provided were resistant to grazing. Higher levels of grazing occurred on Ulva spp. (apical parts) and Z. nolteii, both with periphyton. The presence of periphyton did not change grazing rates. When a choice between each food type was offered, the sediment was clearly the feeding niche preferred by the snails. As P. ulvae spent more time on the sediment (preferred feeding niche), the hypothesis that it has a role in preventing macroalgal blooms was not supported.</abstract></record><record><database name="uleam_endnote.enl" path="uleam_endnote.enl">uleam_endnote.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Araújo, Cristiano V M</author><author>Shinn, Cândida</author><author>Mendes, Lucas B</author><author>Delello-Schneider, Danieli</author><author>Sanchez, André L</author><author>Espíndola, Evaldo L G</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Avoidance response of Danio rerio to a fungicide in a linear contamination gradient</title><secondary-title>Science of the Total Environment</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Science of the Total Environment</full-title></periodical><pages>36-42</pages><volume>484</volume><keywords><keyword>Avoidance behavior</keyword><keyword>Environmental contamination</keyword><keyword>Fish</keyword><keyword>Pyrimethanil</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2014</year></dates><publisher>Elsevier {BV}</publisher><accession-num>24686143</accession-num><electronic-resource-num>10.1016/j.scitotenv.2014.03.037</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.scitotenv.2014.03.037</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>The present study examines the ability of juvenile Danio rerio to avoid pyrimethanil-contaminated water. An avoidance assay system was used with a contamination gradient formed by seven compartments, through which the fish could move and choose the preferred compartment(s). Additionally, the influence of fish movements in promoting the mixing between compartments and thus disruption of the gradient over time was also examined by testing sodium chloride (NaCl) at sublethal concentrations. Samples with pyrimethanil were obtained from the commercial formulation Mythos®, which was applied to mesocosm systems. Samples of the pyrimethanil-contaminated mesocosms water were collected and a series of seven concentrations (0.2 to 1.4mgL-1 plus a control) diluted with reference (uncontaminated) mesocosm water were added to the system to form the gradient. After 4h exposure, fish avoidance in the three highest pyrimethanil concentrations ranged from 29 to 66%. The 4h-AC50 (concentration at which 50% of the fish avoided pyrimethanil after 4h exposure) was 1.10 (confidence interval: 1.07 to 1.12)mgL-1. However, the avoidance pattern after 12h was strongly reduced and it was not possible to calculate the AC50. This is explained by the results of the NaCl experiment, which showed that the movement of fish in the system accelerates the mixing of the solutions between compartments. As pyrimethanil can trigger avoidance response in D. rerio, this fungicide, even at non-lethal concentrations, could be considered an environmental disturber. © 2014 Elsevier B.V.</abstract></record><record><database name="uleam_endnote.enl" path="uleam_endnote.enl">uleam_endnote.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Puello-Cruz, A C</author><author>Gómez, S</author><author>Morales-Serna, F N</author><author>Rodríguez-Valenzuela, P M</author><author>Pelayo-Romero, E A</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Optimal conditions for the culture of Amphiascoides atopus (Harpacticoida: Miraciidae) from Mazatlan Sinaloa State, Mexico</title><secondary-title>Proceedings of the Biological Society of Washington</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Proceedings of the Biological Society of Washington</full-title></periodical><pages>78-86</pages><volume>127</volume><issue>1</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2014</year></dates><publisher>The Biological Society of Washington</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.2988/0006-324x-127.1.78</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.2988/0006-324X-127.1.78</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>The effects of the most important factors (food quality and quantity, temperature, and salinity) on the production of the harpacticoid copepod Amphiascoides atopus Lotufo &amp; Fleeger, originally described from a mass culture system at the Department of Zoology and Physiology of the Louisiana State University at Baton Rouge, were evaluated to ascertain potential yields. For aquacultural purposes, it is important to assess these factors for laboratory-controlled conditions. Feeding treatments were not significantly different between monospecific (Chaetoceros rnuelleri, Isochrysis sp., and Nannochloropsis oculata) and mixed diets (all three of the mentioned diets in ratios of 1:1:1) (527.2 +/- 68.3 to 404.4 +/- 160.6 organisms L-1). Copepods fed diets of 320 cells mu L-1 (539.6 +/- 115.8 organisms L-1) showed the highest mean egg production. Our results demonstrate that a temperature of less than 20 degrees C (15 +/- 3.5 organisms L-1) significantly affected the final mean population counts. No statistical differences were observed at 24, 28, and 32 degrees C with productions varying between 330 +/- 67.4 to 527 +/- 101.3 organisms L-1. Of all the salinity levels tested, the highest population densities were recorded at 32 psu (983.0 +/- 78.8 organisms L-1). Identifying the correct copepod species as live prey for larviculture is also considered important so that the appropriate size and characteristics of the food can be administered. These findings suggest that the copepod A. atopus can serve as a good potential live feed for larviculture.</abstract></record><record><database name="uleam_endnote.enl" path="uleam_endnote.enl">uleam_endnote.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Guzmán Cedeño, Á M</author><author>Zambrano Pazmino, Diego Efren</author><author>Rondón, A J</author><author>Laurencio Silva, Marta</author><author>Perez Quintana, Manuel</author><author>Leon Aguilar, Rolando</author><author>Rivera Fernandez, Ruben</author><author>others</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Isolation, selection and characterization of cellulolytic fungi from soil samples in Manabí-Ecuador.</title><secondary-title>Revista de la Facultad de Ciencias Agrarias, Universidad Nacional de Cuyo</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Revista de la Facultad de Ciencias Agrarias, Universidad Nacional de Cuyo</full-title></periodical><pages>177-189</pages><volume>46</volume><issue>2</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2014</year></dates><publisher>Facultad de Ciencias Agrarias, Universidad Nacional de Cuyo</publisher><urls/><abstract>The research aimed to isolate, select, and characterize cellulolytic filamentous fungi from soil for future implementation as inoculum in the composting of fibrous organic waste. Five sampling environments were considered: organic agriculture (OA); conventional agriculture (AQ); artificial forest (BM); sugarcane area (RC) and compost piles (AC). For the isolation, serial dilutions were plated onto Agar-Sabouraud cellulose. The grown colonies were purified by depletion until obtaining a strain collection of 131cellulolytic fungi. The selection criterion was the growth on nutrient agar with modification of the carbon source by carboxymethylcellulose, and its positive reaction for red congo test, in which clear zones around colonies were observed on 48 cellulolytic fungi, from which fungi that displayed the highest ratio of halo were selected (AO-1, AO-2, AO-4, AO-5, AO-6, AO-8, AQ-3, AQ-8 and RC-3) growth was evaluated at different pH values (3, 5, 7, 9) and temperature (50 -70 degrees C). The AO-8 showed higher halo fungus cellulose hydrolysis with 10.33 mm of growth and stability at different pH and temperature levels; so their growth dynamics are determined by finding logarithmic response until 96 hours; furthermore amylolytic and pectinolytic capacity was evaluated reflecting 11.75 and 2.75 mm, respectively. According to these results, the AO-8 fungus has potential to be used as inoculum for composting.</abstract></record><record><database name="uleam_endnote.enl" path="uleam_endnote.enl">uleam_endnote.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Estupiñán-Montaño, Colombo</author><author>Cedeño-Figueroa, Luis G</author><author>Galván-Magaña, Felipe</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Hábitos alimentarios del tiburón martillo Sphyrna lewini (Griffith &amp; Smith 1834) (Chondrichthyes) en el Pacífico ecuatoriano</title><secondary-title>Revista de biología marina y oceanografía</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Revista de biología marina y oceanografía</full-title></periodical><pages>379-386</pages><volume>44</volume><issue>2</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2009</year></dates><publisher>{SciELO} Comision Nacional de Investigacion Cientifica Y Tecnologica ({CONICYT})</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.4067/s0718-19572009000200011</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.4067/S0718-19572009000200011</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>This study analyzed the diet of 116 specimens of scalloped hammerhead, Sphyrna lewini caught by the shark fleet in the Ecuadorian Pacific. The sampling was between January and December 2004. The index of relative importance (%) showed the highest values for the cephalopods Histioteuthis spp. (22.7%) and Dosidicus gigas (21.9%). In relation to feeding by maturity stage and sex, the juvenile females predated mainly on D. gigas (58.5%); whereas the adult females feed mainly on Octopus spp. (47.6%), Histioteuthis spp. (18.7%) and Sthenoteuthis oualaniensis (16.3%). The juvenile males fed on cephalopods Mastigoteuthis spp. (12.1), Histioteuthis spp. (10.2) and Ancistrocheirus lesueuri (7.9), while the adult males predated on D. gigas (53.7%) and Histioteuthis spp. (14.9%). Considering the prey habitat, S. lewini is an oceanic predator which consumed oceanic prey, mainly cephalopods; whereas the juvenile sharks can predate on oceanic cephalopods and also on coastal prey from benthic habitat such as fish and crustaceans.</abstract></record><record><database name="uleam_endnote.enl" path="uleam_endnote.enl">uleam_endnote.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Araújo, Cristiano V M</author><author>Shinn, Cândida</author><author>Vasconcelos, Ana M.</author><author>Ribeiro, Rui</author><author>Espíndola, Evaldo L G</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Preference and avoidance responses by tadpoles: The fungicide pyrimethanil as a habitat disturber</title><secondary-title>Ecotoxicology</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Ecotoxicology</full-title></periodical><pages>851-860</pages><volume>23</volume><issue>5</issue><keywords><keyword>Escape</keyword><keyword>Evasion</keyword><keyword>Median preferred concentration</keyword><keyword>Migration</keyword><keyword>Non-forced exposure</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2014</year></dates><publisher>Kluwer Academic Publishers</publisher><urls/><abstract>Tadpoles of two amphibian species, the neotropical anuran Leptodactylus latrans and the North American bullfrog Lithobates catesbeianus, were used in experiments to assess their preferred spatial distribution along habitat gradients and, thus, to what extent contamination by the fungicide pyrimethanil could trigger active spatial avoidance. The tadpoles were tested in a non-confined multi-compartment static system with a pyrimethanil contamination gradient through which organisms could move freely. Two samples, with and without (reference) pyrimethanil contamination, taken from outdoor mesocosms, were assayed. Tadpoles showed to be able to detect and move to the most favorable environment by preferring compartments containing reference mesocosm water. Pyrimethanil concentrations from 0.2 to 1.4 mg L(-1) were below lethal levels, but acted as habitat disturber since spatial avoidance was triggered. Avoiders of L. latrans reached almost 50 % at 1.4 mg L(-1). The present data reinforces the hypothesis regarding the risk of plant protection products to act, not only as toxicants, but also as habitat disturber, potentially leading to avoidance-driven population decline of amphibians.</abstract></record><record><database name="uleam_endnote.enl" path="uleam_endnote.enl">uleam_endnote.enl</database><ref-type name="Newspaper Article">5</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Araújo, Cristiano V M</author><author>Moreira-Santos, Matilde</author><author>Sousa, JoséP P.</author><author>Ochoa-Herrera, Valeria</author><author>Encalada, Andrea C.</author><author>Ribeiro, Rui</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Active avoidance from a crude oil soluble fraction by an Andean paramo copepod</title><secondary-title>Ecotoxicology</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Ecotoxicology</full-title></periodical><keywords><keyword>Ecuador</keyword><keyword>Non-forced exposure</keyword><keyword>Oil spill</keyword><keyword>Paramo</keyword><keyword>Polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2014</year></dates><urls/><abstract>Several oil spills due to ruptures in the pipeline oil systems have occurred at the Andean paramo. A sample of this crude oil was mixed with water from a nearby Andean lagoon and the toxicity of the soluble fraction was assessed through lethal and avoidance assays with a locally occurring copepod (Boeckella occidentalis intermedia). The integration of mortality and avoidance aimed at predicting the immediate decline of copepod populations facing an oil leakage. The 24-h median lethal PAH concentration was 42.7 (26.4-91.6) µg L(-1). In the 12-h avoidance assay, 30 % avoidance was recorded at the highest PAH concentration (19.4 µg L(-1)). The mortality at this PAH concentration would be of 25 % and, thus, the population immediate decline would be of 55 %. The inclusion of non-forced exposure testing with the quantification of the avoidance response in environmental risk assessments is, therefore, supported due to underestimation of the lethal assays.</abstract></record></records></xml>
